(squeaks)
♪ Her face is a map of the
world Is a map of the world ♪
♪ You can see
she's a beautiful girl
She's a beautiful girl ♪
♪ And everything around her
is a silver pool of light ♪
♪ People who surround her
feel the benefit of it ♪
♪ It makes you calm ♪
♪ She'll hold you captivated
in her palm ♪
♪ Suddenly I see ♪
♪ This is what I wanna be ♪
♪ Why the hell
it means so much to me ♪
♪ And I feel like
walking the world
Like walking the world ♪
♪ And you can hear
she's a beautiful girl
She's a beautiful girl ♪
♪ She fills up every corner
like she's born
in black and white ♪
♪ Makes you feel warmer
when you're trying
to remember ♪
♪ What you heard ♪
-♪ She likes to leave you
hanging on a word ♪
-Good luck.
♪ Suddenly I see
this is what I wanna be ♪
-♪ Suddenly I see ♪
-(children giggling)
♪ Why the hell
it means so much to me ♪
-♪ Suddenly I see ♪
-♪ This is what I want to be ♪
♪ Suddenly I see ♪
♪ Why the hell
it means so much to me ♪
♪ And she's taller than most ♪
♪ And she's looking at me ♪
♪ I can see her eyes
lookin' from the page
in a magazine ♪
♪ Suddenly I see ♪
♪ She's got the power
to be the power to give
♪ The power to see
yeah, yeah ♪
♪ She's got the power to be
the power to give ♪
-♪ The power to see
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
-(horn honks)
-♪ Suddenly I see ♪
-♪ She's got the power to be ♪
♪ The power to give
the power to see, yeah, yeah ♪
-♪ Suddenly I see ♪
-♪ She's got the power to be
the power to give ♪
♪ The power to see, yeah, yeah
Suddenly I see ♪
-♪ Suddenly I see ♪
-♪ This is what I want to be ♪
♪ Why the hell
it means so much to me ♪
-♪ Suddenly I see ♪
-♪ This is what I want to be ♪
♪ Why the hell
it means so much to me ♪
-♪ Suddenly I see ♪
-♪ Oh, oh, yeah, yeah ♪
-♪ Why the hell it means
so much to me, yeah, yeah ♪
-♪ Suddenly I see ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Why the hell
it means so much to me ♪
(bell dings)
Hi. Uh, I have an appointment
with Emily Charlton?
-Andrea Sachs?
-Yes.
Great. Human Resources
certainly has an odd
sense of humor.
Follow me.
Okay, so I was Miranda's
second assistant,
but her first assistant
recently got promoted,
and so now I'm the first.
-Oh, and you're
replacing yourself.
-Well, I am trying.
Miranda sacked
the last two girls
after only a few weeks.
We need to find someone
who can survive here.
Do you understand?
Yeah. Of course.
Who's Miranda?
Oh, my God.
I will pretend you did not
just ask me that.
She's the editor in chief
of Runway, not to mention
a legend.
You work a year for her,
and you can get a job
at any magazine you want.
A million girls
would kill for this job.
It sounds like
a great opportunity.
I'd love to be considered.
(giggling)
Andrea, Runway
is a fashion magazine,
so an interest in fashion
is crucial.
What makes you think
I'm not interested in fashion?
-(cell phone ringing)
-Oh, my God.
No! No! No!
What's wrong?
She's on her way.
Tell everyone!
She's not supposed to
be here until 9:00.
Her driver just text messaged,
and her facialist
ruptured a disk.
-God, these people!
-(whistles, whispers)
Who's that?
That I can't
even talk about.
All right, everyone!
Gird your loins!
-(excited chattering)
-Did someone eat
an onion bagel?
(exhales, sniffs)
(bell dings)
Sorry, Miranda.
Move it! Ooh!
I don't understand
why it's so difficult
to confirm an appointment.
I know. I'm so sorry,
Miranda. I actually did
confirm last night.
Details
of your incompetence
do not interest me.
Tell Simone I'm not going
to approve that girl
that she sent me
for the Brazilian layout.
I asked for clean, athletic,
smiling. She sent me dirty,
tired and paunchy.
And RSVP yes
to the Michael Kors party.
I want the driver
to drop me off at 9:30
and pick me up at 9:45 sharp.
-(whispers) 9:45 sharp.
-Call Natalie at Glorious Foods,
tell her no for the 40th time.
No, I don't want dacquoise.
I want tortes filled
with warm rhubarb compote.
Then call my ex-husband and
remind him the parent-teacher
conference is at Dalton tonight.
Then call my husband, ask him
to meet me for dinner at that
place I went to with Massimo.
Also, tell Richard I saw the
pictures that he sent
for that feature
on the female paratroopers,
and they're all
so deeply unattractive.
Is it impossible to find
a lovely, slender female
paratrooper?
-No.
-Am I reaching for the stars
here? Not really.
Also, I need to see all
the things that Nigel has pulled
for Gwyneth's second cover try.
I wonder if she's lost
any of that weight yet.
Who's that?
Nobody. Um, uh--
Human Resources sent her up
about the new assistant job,
and I was preinterviewing her.
But she's hopeless
and totally wrong for it.
Clearly I'm going to have
to do that myself because
the last two you sent me
were completely inadequate.
So send her in.
That's all.
Right.
-She wants to see you.
-Oh! She does?
Move!
-This is foul.
Don't let her see it. Go!
-That's--
(sighs)
Who are you?
Uh, my name
is Andy Sachs.
I recently graduated
from Northwestern University.
And what are you doing here?
(clears throat)
Well, I think
I could do a good job
as your assistant.
And, um--
Yeah, I came to New York
to be a journalist and sent
letters out everywhere
and then finally got a call
from Elias-Clarke
and met with Sherry
up at Human Resources.
Basically, it's this
or Auto Universe.
-So you don't read Runway?
-Uh, no.
And before today,
you had never heard of me.
No.
And you have no style
or sense of fashion.
Well, um, I think that
depends on what you're--
No, no.
That wasn't a question.
Um, I was editor in chief
of the Daily Northwestern.
I also, um, won
a national competition
for college journalists
with my series
on the Janitors' Union,
which exposed the exploitation--
That's all.
(scoffs)
Yeah. You know, okay.
You're right.
I don't fit in here.
I am not skinny
or glamorous,
and I don't know that much
about fashion.
But I'm smart.
I learn fast
and I will work very hard.
I got the exclusive
on the Cavalli for Gwyneth,
but the problem is,
with that huge feathered
headdress that she's wearing,
she looks like
she's working the main stage
at the Golden Nugget.
Thank you for your time.
Who is that sad,
little person?
Are we doing
a before-and-after piece
I don't know about?
Brown and Law, please?
Thank you.
-Andrea.
-Hmm?
Wait. You got a job
at a fashion magazine?
-Mm-hmm.
-What was it, a phone interview?
-WOMAN: Wow.
-Ow! Don't be a jerk.
Miranda Priestly is famous
for being unpredictable.
Okay, Doug. How is it
that you know who she is
and I didn't?
-I'm actually a girl.
-Oh!
-That would explain so much.
-DOUG: Look, seriously.
Miranda Priestly is a huge deal.
I bet a million girls
would kill for that job.
Yeah, great.
The thing is
I'm not one of them.
WOMAN:
Look, you gotta start
somewhere, right?
I mean, look at this dump
Nate works in.
I mean, come on.
Paper napkins? Hello.
Yeah. And Lily, she works
at that gallery doing,
uh, you know--
Oh, I'm sorry.
What exactly is it
that you do anyway?
Well, lucky for me,
I already have my dream job.
(with Lily)
You're a corporate
research analyst!
-Oh, you're right.
My job sucks.
-No!
-It sucks.
I don't-- It's boring.
-It's all right. Breathe.
-I'm trying.
-Here. Take a drink.
-I will have a drink.
-Ah, yes.
I'd like to propose a toast.
To jobs that pay the rent.
-To jobs that pay the rent.
-Jobs that pay the rent.
Oh, baby. You should see
the way these girls
at Runway dress.
I don't have a thing
to wear to work.
Come on. You're gonna
be answering phones
and getting coffee.
You need a ball gown
for that?
I think I might.
Well, I happen to think
you look great always.
Aww! I think
you're full of it.
(giggling)
-Hey. Come on. Let's go home.
-Yeah.
I can think of something
we can do that doesn't
require any clothing.
-Really?
-Mmm.
(up-tempo music playing)
-(phone ringing)
-♪ I haven't got
much time to waste ♪
-♪ It's time to make my way ♪
-Hello?
Andrea, Miranda decided
to kill the autumn jacket
story for September,
and she is pulling up
the Sedona shoot from October.
You need to come into the office
right this second and pick up
her coffee order on the way.
-Now?
-Now, get a pen
and write this down.
I want one
no-foam skimmed latte
with an extra shot
and three drip coffees
with room for milk.
-Searing hot.
And I mean hot.
-(line clicks)
-♪ Are you ready to jump ♪
-(cell phone ringing)
-♪ Get ready to jump ♪
-Hello?
-EMILY: Where are you?
-Oh, I'm almost there. Yeah.
-♪ I'm ready to jump ♪
-Shoot! Oh!
Is there some reason
that my coffee isn't here?
Has she died or something?
No. (whispers) God.
Oh. Bloody time.
-I hope you know that this
is a very difficult job--
-Mm-hm.
for which you are
totally wrong.
And if you mess up,
my head is on
the chopping block.
Now, hang that up.
Don't just fling it
anywhere.
Okay. First of all,
you and I answer the phones.
The phone must be answered
every single time it rings.
Calls roll to voice mail,
and she gets very upset.
If I'm not here--
Andrea, Andrea--
you are chained
to that desk.
-Well, what if I need to--
-What? No.
One time an assistant left
the desk because she sliced her
hand open with a letter opener,
and Miranda
missed Lagerfeld...
just before he boarded
a 17-hour flight
to Australia.
She now works
at TV Guide.
-Man the desk at all times.
Got it.
-(phone rings)
-Uh--
-Miranda Priestly's office.
No, she's not available.
-Who is it?
-(mouthing words)
Yes, I will tell her
you called... yet again.
-(bell chimes)
-Right, remember, you and I
have totally different jobs.
I mean, you get coffee--
(scoffs) and you run errands.
Yet I am in charge
of her schedule,
her appointments
and her expenses.
And, um,
most importantly, um,
I get to go with her to Paris
for Fashion Week in the fall.
I get to wear couture.
I go to all the shows
and all the parties.
I meet all of the designers.
It's divine.
Okay. Now, stay here.
I'm going to the art department
to give them the Book.
-The--
-This is the Book.
Now, it is a mock-up
of everything
-in the current issue.
-Mm-hm.
And we deliver it to Miranda's
apartment every night,
and she retu-- Don't touch it.
She returns it to us
in the morning with her notes.
Now, the second assistant
is supposed to do this,
but Miranda is very private
and she does not like
strangers in her house.
So until she decides
that you are not
a total psycho,
I get the lovely task
of waiting around
for the Book.
-(phone rings)
-Oh, Emily? What do I do--
-Deal with it.
-(rings)
(sighs)
(rings)
Hello.
Mrs. Priestly's office.
Hmm. That's what I meant.
Miranda Priestly's office.
(groans)
Um, you know,
she is in a meeting.
Can I please take a message?
Uh-huh.
Okay. Can you please
spell Gabbana?
-(line clicks)
-Hello?
I guess not.
I guessed
an eight and a half.
Um, uh, that's
very nice of you,
but I don't think
I need these.
Miranda hired me.
She knows what I look like.
-Do you?
-(chuckles)
Emily.
Emily?
She means you.
-MAN: We just cut on the bias.
-MIRANDA: That's not
what I asked you.
I couldn't have been clearer.
There you are, Emily.
-How many times do I have
to scream your name?
-Actually, it's Andy.
My name is Andy.
Andrea, but, uh,
everybody calls me Andy.
(chuckles)
I need 10 or 15 skirts
from Calvin Klein.
-What kind of skirts do you--
-Please bore someone else
with your questions.
And make sure we have Pier 59
at 8:00 a.m. tomorrow.
Remind Jocelyn I need
to see a few of those satchels
that Marc is doing in the pony.
And then tell Simone
I'll take Jackie if Maggie
isn't available.
-Did Demarchelier confirm?
-D-Did D-Demarchel--
Demarchelier. Did he--
Get him on the phone.
Uh, o-- okay.
-And, Emily?
-Yes?
That's all.
It's just
the cavalier disregard
for clear directions--
(chattering continues)
Do you have Demarchelier?
Uh, Demarchelier.
-(groans) Leave it.
-Do you have--
I have Miranda
Priestly calling.
I have Patrick!
Uh, no, she called me
in there and-and then
she asked me about Pier 59.
And there was something
about Simone, Frankie,
someone else.
And, um, she needs skirts
from Calvin Klein.
And, uh, there was
something about a pony.
-Did she say which skirts?
-No. No.
-Did she say what kind?
Color, shape, fabric?
-I tried to ask her.
You may never ask
Miranda anything.
Right. I will deal
with all of this, and you
will go to Calvin Klein.
Eh-- Me?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Do you have some
prior commitment?
Some hideous skirt convention
you have to go to?
Uh--
-(cell phone rings)
-Miranda?
-Are you there?
-I'm about to walk in.
I'll call you as soon as--
(line clicks)
-(cell phone rings)
-(horn honks)
-Hello? Hi.
-EMILY: While you're out,
Miranda needs you to go
to Hermès to pick up 25
scarves we ordered for her.
-Okay.
-Cassidy forgot her homework
at Dalton.
Pick that up. Oh, yeah,
and Miranda went out
to meet with Meisel,
and she will want more
Starbucks when she gets back.
-Hot Starbucks.
-Can you just repeat
that first--
-(dial tone hums)
-Hello?
Oh, my God.
What took you so long?
I have to pee!
What? You haven't peed
since I left?
No, I haven't.
I've been manning the desk,
haven't I? I'm bursting.
Oh, hi.
-(snaps fingers)
-You do coat. Do the coat!
Okay.
Now, be prepared.
The run-through
is at 12:30.
And people are panicking,
so the phone is going to
be ringing off the hook.
The ru--
The run-through. Right.
Yes. Editors bring in
options for the shoot,
and Miranda chooses.
She chooses every single
thing in every single issue.
Run-throughs are a huge deal.
I don't know why you don't
know that, Andrea.
-WOMAN: Okay. Are you ready?
-EMILY: Oh, hi, hi.
Right. Well, after the loo,
Serena and I are going to lunch.
-This is her-- the new me.
-Hi.
-Told you.
-I thought you were kidding.
No, quite serious, yeah.
I get 20 minutes for lunch,
and you get 15.
-When I come back, you can go.
-Okay.
SERENA:
What exactly is she wearing?
(giggling)
Her grandmother's skirt.
Hmm. Corn chowder.
That's an interesting choice.
You do know that cellulite
is one of the main ingredients
in corn chowder.
So none of the girls here
eat anything?
Not since two
became the new four
and zero became the new two.
-Well, I'm a six.
-Which is the new 14.
Oh. Shoot.
Oh, never mind.
I'm sure you have plenty more
polyblend where that came from.
-(cash register clicking)
-Okay. You think
my clothes are hideous.
I get it.
But, you know,
I'm not going to be
in fashion forever,
so I don't see the point of
changing everything about myself
just because I have this job.
Yes, that's true.
That's really what this
multibillion-dollar industry
is all about anyway, isn't it?
-Inner beauty.
-(cell phone rings)
Hello.
Right. Come on.
-Miranda's pushed the
run-through up a half an hour.
-Mmm!
-She's always
15 minutes early.
-Which means?
-You're already late. Come.
-Shoot!
Excuse me.
(bell dings)
-Mr. Ravitz.
-Nigel.
-Issue going well?
-Oh, yes.
Our best September ever.
Great. Heard Miranda
killed autumn jackets
and pulled up the Sedona shoot.
What's that
costing me?
About 300,000.
Must have been
some lousy jackets.
-Irv Ravitz.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
This is Andy Sachs,
Miranda's new assistant.
Congratulations,
young lady.
A million girls
would kill for that job.
Bye-bye.
-Hmm?
-Chairman of Elias-Clarke,
Irv Ravitz.
You know what they say?
Tiny man, huge ego.
No. And I've seen
all this before.
Theyskens is trying
to reinvent the drop waist,
so actually it's--
-Where are all
the other dresses?
-We have some right here.
-Stand, watch and listen.
-And I think it can be
very interesting--
No. No, I just--
It's just baffling to me.
Why is it so impossible
to put together
a decent run-through?
You people have had
hours and hours to prepare.
It's just so confusing to me.
Where are
the advertisers?
-We have some pieces
from Banana Republic.
-We need more, don't we?
Oh. This is-- This might be--
What do you think of--
Yeah. Well, you know me.
Give me a full ballerina skirt
and a hint of saloon
and I'm on board.
But do you think
it's too much like--
Like the Lacroix from July?
I thought that, but no,
not with the right accessories.
It should work.
Where are
the belts for this dre--
Why is no one ready?
Here.
It's a tough call.
-They're so different.
-MIRANDA: Hmm.
(snorts, chuckles)
Something funny?
No. No, no. Nothing's--
You know, it's just
that both those belts look
exactly the same to me.
You know, I'm still learning
about this stuff and, uh--
"This... stuff"?
Oh. Okay. I see.
You think this has
nothing to do with you.
You go to your closet...
and you select-- I don't know--
that lumpy blue sweater,
for instance,
because you're trying
to tell the world that you
take yourself too seriously
to care about what
you put on your back.
But what you don't know
is that that sweater
is not just blue.
It's not turquoise.
It's not lapis.
It's actually cerulean.
And you're also blithely
unaware of the fact
that in 2002,
Oscar de la Renta did a
collection of cerulean gowns.
And then I think it
was Yves Saint Laurent--
wasn't it--
who showed cerulean
military jackets?
-I think we need
a jacket here.
-Mmm.
And then cerulean quickly
showed up in the collections
of eight different designers.
And then it, uh,
filtered down through
the department stores
and then trickled on down
into some tragic
Casual Corner,
where you, no doubt,
fished it out of
some clearance bin.
However, that blue
represents millions
of dollars
and countless jobs,
and it's sort of comical
how you think that you've
made a choice
that exempts you
from the fashion industry,
when, in fact,
you're wearing a sweater
that was selected for you
by the people in this room,
from a pile of stuff.
ANDY: So then I said,
"No, I couldn't see
the difference
between the two
absolutely identical belts,"
and you should have seen
the look she gave me!
I thought the flesh was
gonna melt off her face.
-(chuckles)
-It's not funny.
She's not happy unless everyone
around her is panicked,
nauseous or suicidal.
And the Clackers
just worship her.
-The who?
-They call them Clackers.
The sound that their stilettos
make in the marble lobby.
It's like,
"Clack, clack, clack.
clack, clack."
(groans) And they all
act like they're curing
cancer or something.
(chuckling)
The amount of time
and energy
that these people spend on
these insignificant, minute
details, and for what?
So that tomorrow they can
spend another $300,000
reshooting something
that was probably fine
to begin with
to sell people things
they don't need!
God!
-I'm not even hungry anymore.
-What?
-That is why those girls
are so skinny.
-Oh. No, no, no.
Give me that.
There's, like, eight dollars
of Jarlsberg in there.
(sighs)
You know what?
I just have to
stick it out for a year.
One year.
And then I can do what I
came to New York to do.
But I can't let Miranda
get to me.
-I won't.
-Easy there, tiger.
-Oh, good morning, Miranda.
-Get me Isaac.
I don't see my breakfast here.
Are my eggs here?
Where are my eggs?
Excuse me!
Pick up the Polaroids
from the lingerie shoot.
Have the brakes checked
on my car.
-(truck horn honking)
-(gasps)
Where's that piece of paper
I had in my hand
yesterday morning?
The girls need new surfboards
or Boogie boards or something
for Spring Break.
-Hello.
-The twins also
need flip-flops.
-Ow!
-Oh, my gosh!
Pick up my shoes from Blahnik,
and then go get Patricia.
-Who's that?
-Good girl! Good girl!
Good girl!
Get me that
little table that I liked
at that store on Madison.
Get us a reservation
for dinner tonight at that place
that got the good review.
-Get me Isaac.
-Thirty-six thank-you notes
delivered today.
-Where is everyone?
-Why is no one working?
(Miranda's voice overlapping)
Get me Demarchelier.
I have Miranda Priestly
calling for-- Okay.
I have Patrick.
(sighs) Thank God
it's Friday, right?
At least Miranda will be
in Miami, so we don't have
to be on call this weekend.
You know, my dad's
coming in from Ohio.
Yeah, we're gonna
go out to dinner,
maybe see Chicago.
You doing anything fun
this weekend?
Yes.
(piano music playing)
ANDY:
Yeah, Nate said it was great.
He actually--
He applied here, but they wanted
someone with more experience.
-Here.
-Huh? What's this?
I don't want you
to get behind
on your rent.
-Dad, how did you--
-It's--
I'm gonna kill Mom.
(chuckles)
Dad, thank you.
Mm-hmm.
-It's really good to see you.
-You too, honey.
So, you want to
start grilling me now,
or should we wait
till after dinner?
I thought
I'd let you at least enjoy
the bread basket first.
No, no, no. It's okay.
Go right ahead.
We're just
a little worried, honey.
We get e-mails
from you at your office
at 2:00 a.m.
Your pay is terrible.
You don't get
to write anything.
Hey, that's not fair.
I wrote those e-mails.
I'm just trying to understand
why someone who got accepted
to Stanford Law
turns it down
to be a journalist, and now
you're not even doing that.
Dad, you have to trust me.
Being Miranda's assistant
opens a lot of doors.
Emily is going
to Paris with Miranda
in a few months,
and she's gonna meet
editors and writers
from every important magazine.
And in a year,
that could be me.
-All right?
-Mm-hmm.
Dad, I swear,
this is my break.
-This is my-- my chance.
-(cell phone ringing)
This is... my boss.
-I'm sorry, Dad.
I have to take this.
-Take it. Take it.
-Hello. Miranda?
-My flight has been canceled.
It's some absurd
weather problem.
I need to get home tonight.
The twins have a recital
tomorrow morning at school.
-What?
-At school!
-Absolutely.
Let me see what I can do.
-Oh, good.
Hi. Um, I know this
is totally last minute,
but I was hoping that you
could maybe get a flight
for my boss
from Miami
to New York tonight?
Uh--
ANDY: Yeah, any kind of jet.
-From Miami to New York.
-Thank you.
-Yup, I need it tonight.
I need it--
-Ow!
-I thought you were
going out the other--
-Sweetie! No.
-It's over here, honey.
-Tonight.
Hi. I'm trying to get
a flight tonight-- for tonight--
from Miami to New York.
Yes, I know
there's a hurricane.
Nothing is flying out?
What do you mean,
nothing is flying out?
It's for Miranda Priestly,
and I know that she's
a client of yours.
Yes. Yes, hi.
I need a jet tonight
from Miami to New York.
-Yeah. Sorry. Hold on.
-Hello? Miranda, hi.
I'm trying to get you a flight,
but no one is flying out
because of the weather.
Please. It's just--
I don't know-- drizzling.
-(thunderclap)
-Someone must be getting out.
Call Donatella.
Get her jet.
Call everybody else
that we know that has
a jet. Irv?
Call every--
This is your responsibi--
This is your job.
Get me home.
Oh, my God!
She's going to murder me.
What does she want you to do,
call the National Guard and have
her airlifted out of there?
Of course not.
Could I do that?
Come on. Come on.
The girls' recital
was absolutely wonderful.
They played Rachmaninoff.
Everyone loved it.
Everyone except me,
because, sadly,
I was not there.
Miranda,
I'm so sorry.
Do you know why
I hired you?
I always hire
the same girl--
stylish,
slender, of course,
worships the magazine.
But so often,
they turn out to be--
I don't know--
disappointing and, um,
stupid.
So you, with that
impressive resume
and the big speech about
your so-called work ethic--
I, um-- I thought you
would be different.
I said to myself,
go ahead.
Take a chance.
Hire the smart, fat girl.
(clears throat)
I had hope.
My God. I live on it.
Anyway, you ended up
disappointing me
more than, um--
more than any
of the other silly girls.
Um, I really
did everything
I could think of.
-Uh--
-That's all.
Excuse me!
Where do you think
you're going?
She hates me, Nigel.
And that's my problem
because--
Oh, wait.
No, it's not my problem.
I don't know what else I can do
because if I do something right,
it's unacknowledged.
She doesn't even
say thank you.
But if I do something wrong,
she is vicious.
-So quit.
-What?
-Quit.
-Quit?
I can get another girl to take
your job in five minutes--
one who really wants it.
No, I don't want to quit.
That's not fair.
But, you know,
I'm just saying that I would
just like a little credit
for the fact that I'm
killing myself trying.
Andy, be serious.
You are not trying.
-You are whining.
-I--
What is it that you want me
to say to you, huh?
Do you want me to say,
"Poor you. Miranda's picking
on you. Poor you. Poor Andy"?
Hmm? Wake up, six.
She's just doing her job.
Don't you know that you
are working at the place
that published some
of the greatest artists
of the century?
Halston, Lagerfeld,
de la Renta.
And what they did,
what they created,
was greater than art
because you live
your life in it.
Well, not you, obviously,
but some people.
You think this is
just a magazine, hmm?
This is not just
a magazine.
This is a shining
beacon of hope for--
oh, I don't know--
let's say a young boy
growing up in Rhode Island
with six brothers,
pretending to go to soccer
practice when he was really
going to sewing class
and reading Runway
under the covers at night
with a flashlight.
You have no idea
how many legends
have walked these halls.
And what's worse,
you don't care.
Because this place,
where so many people
would die to work,
you only deign to work.
And you want to know why
she doesn't kiss you
on the forehead
and give you a gold star
on your homework
at the end of the day.
Wake up, sweetheart.
(sighs)
-Okay. So I'm screwing it up.
-Mmm.
I don't want to.
I just wish that I knew
what I could do to--
-(sighs) Nigel?
-Hmm?
Nigel, Nigel.
No.
I don't know what
you expect me to do.
There's nothing
in this whole closet
that'll fit a size six.
I can guarantee you.
These are all sample sizes--
two and four.
-All right. We're doing
this for you. And--
-A poncho?
You'll take what I give you
and you'll like it.
-We're doing this Dolce
for you.
-Hmm!
And shoes.
-Jimmy Choo's.
-Hmm.
-Manolo Blahnik.
-Wow.
Nancy Gonzalez.
Love that.
Okay, Narciso Rodriguez.
This we love.
-Uh, it might fit.
It might.
-What?
Okay. Now, Chanel. You're
in desperate need of Chanel.
Darling, shall we?
We have to get to the
beauty department, and God knows
how long that's going to take.
(groans)
I mean, I have no idea
why Miranda hired her.
Me neither.
The other day, we were
in the beauty department.
She held up
the Shu Uemura eyelash curler
and said, "What is this?"
(laughing)
I just knew from
the moment I saw her,
she was going
to be a complete
and utter disas--
-(phone rings)
-Miranda Priestly's office.
No, actually,
she's not available,
but I'll leave word.
Okay, thanks. Bye.
(clears throat)
How did--
(scoffs)
-Are you wearing the--
-The Chanel boots?
Yeah, I am.
You look good.
-Oh, God.
-What?
-She does.
-Oh, shut up, Serena.
-See you guys tomorrow.
-Good night, man.
Take it easy.
Take care
of that finger, huh?
So, what do you think?
Uh, I think we better
get out of here
before my girlfriend
sees me.
♪ Look around
Everywhere you turn
it's heartache ♪
♪ It's everywhere
that you go ♪
♪ Look around ♪
♪ You try everything
you can to escape ♪
-♪ The pain of life
that you know ♪
-(horn honking)
-♪ The life that you know ♪
-♪ If all else fails
and you long to be ♪
♪ Something better
than you are today ♪
♪ I know a place
where you can get away ♪
♪ It's called a dance floor ♪
-♪ And here's what it's for ♪
-(cell phone rings)
♪ Come on, vogue ♪
♪ Let your body move
to the music ♪
-♪ Move to the music ♪
-♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ Come on, vogue ♪
-♪ Vogue ♪
-♪ Beauty's where you find it ♪
-The gowns are fabulous.
Mm-hmm. We're gonna
use the burgundy.
♪ Vogue ♪
♪ Ooh, you've got to just ♪
-Gotta find--
-♪ Let your body
go with the flow ♪
So we spent a whole semester
on potatoes alone.
You take the fry
and squeeze it.
-See how firm that is?
-Hey. Oh, I'm so sorry
I'm late.
There was a crisis
in the accessories department.
-I needed to find
a python headband.
-Python's hot right now.
I have exciting presents
for all of you.
Are you ready?
-What is that?
-It's a Bang & Olufsen phone.
Charlie Rose
sent it to Miranda
for her birthday.
I looked it up on line.
It's $1,100.
-What?
-Wow!
And I have some products.
Mason Pearson hairbrushes.
-A little Clinique.
-Ooh!
-Oh, damn it.
I love your job.
-Oh! One more.
-A little thing.
-(gasps)
-Do you want it?
You want-- Oh.
-Gimme! Gimme, gimme, gimme!
-I think she likes it.
-Oh, my God! This is
the new Marc Jacobs!
This is sold out everywhere.
Where did you get this?
Miranda didn't
want it, so--
No, no, no, no, no.
This bag is, like, $1,900.
I cannot take this from you.
-(cackles)
-Yeah, you can.
-Why do women need so many bags?
-Shut up.
You have one.
You put all your junk in it,
and that's it. You're done.
Fashion is not
about utility.
An accessory
is merely a piece
of iconography
used to express
individual identity.
-Oh! And it's pretty.
-That too.
Yeah. But the thing is,
it turns out
there is more to Runway
than just fancy purses.
Look, here's an essay
by Jay McInerney,
a piece by Joan Didion.
Even an interview
with Christiane Amanpour.
-Looks like someone's
been drinking the Kool-Aid.
-What are you--
-(cell phone ringing)
-I got it. It's--
Yup, the Dragon Lady.
-Oh, Miranda?
-Let me talk to her.
-I need that.
-I'll tell her to get
her own scrambled eggs.
Lily, no, no, no!
Put that thing up!
I was gonna answer it!
It's gonna make--
Give me the... phone.
(beeps)
-(laughs)
-Hi, Miranda.
Ooh. Shh.
Absolutely.
-Shh!
-Uh-huh. I'm leaving right now.
You know, you guys
didn't have to be
such assholes.
(rings)
(electronic music playing)
Um, excuse me.
I'm looking
for James Holt.
Um, that's him
right there.
-Oh. Thanks.
-No problem.
-I put my stuff out there,
and I pray they improve.
-Really?
-Excuse me.
-Hi.
I'm Andy. I'm picking up
for Miranda Priestly.
Oh, yes. You must be
the new Emily.
-(chuckling)
-Nice to meet you.
-Oh, let me see that bag.
Very, very nice.
-Ah.
Distressed, studded leather,
pieced by hand, finished
with a metallic fringe.
(clicks tongue)
Very nice, indeed. Who made
that fantastic thing?
You.
Hmm. Duh. This way.
Uh, here we go.
It's a sketch
of Miranda's dress
for the benefit.
Also the centerpiece
of my spring collection.
Top secret stuff.
-I'll guard it with my life.
-Please do.
Come on. You're working
for Miranda Priestly now.
You must be
in desperate need
of hard liquor.
Excuse us, girls.
She'll have the punch.
(clears throat)
It's deadly. Have fun.
(up-tempo music playing)
♪ And that you never seem
to be in short supply of ♪
-He's right, you know.
-Hmm?
The punch. I drank it
at James's last party.
I woke up in Hoboken
wearing nothing but a poncho
and a cowboy hat.
-♪ You know
I've wanted you so long ♪
-Ah. Well.
-Wise.
-(chuckling)
-Uh, hi.
-Christian Thompson.
Christian Thompson?
You're kidding.
No, you're--
You write for, like,
every magazine I love.
I actually-- I reviewed
your collection of essays
for my college newspaper.
Did you mention my good looks
and my killer charm?
-No, but--
-What do you do?
Oh. Well, I want to work
for somewhere
like The New Yorker
or Vanity Fair.
-I am a writer too.
-Is that right?
-Mm-hmm.
-I should read your stuff.
Why don't you send it over?
Yeah?
That would be-- Thank you.
That would be great.
(giggling)
But actually, right now,
I'm working as Miranda
Priestly's assistant.
Oh, you're kidding.
Well, that's too bad.
That's-- Whoa. You'll
never survive Miranda.
-Excuse me?
-Well, you seem nice, smart.
You can't do that job.
Gotta go.
Okay.
Well, it was very, very nice
to meet you, Miranda girl.
Emily?
Call James Holt's office.
Tell them I want to move the
preview up to today at 12:30.
Tell everybody else.
Be ready to leave
in half an hour.
But we're not expected
until Tuesday.
Did she say why?
Yes. Yeah,
she explained every detail
of her decision making.
And then we brushed
each other's hair and gabbed
about American Idol.
I see your point.
-ANDY: What's a preview anyway?
-Good morning, Miranda.
NIGEL: Miranda insists
upon seeing
all the designers' collections
before they show them.
-Great to see you.
-Hello, James.
ANDY: And she
tells them what she thinks?
NIGEL: In her way.
Uh, this season
really began for me
with a meditation
on the intersection
between East and West.
NIGEL: There's a scale.
One nod is good.
Two nods is very good.
There's only been one actual
smile on record, and that was
Tom Ford in 2001.
An obi belt.
NIGEL:
She doesn't like it,
she shakes her head.
This is the dress that we
have designed specifically
and exclusively for you.
NIGEL: Then, of course,
there's the pursing
of the lips.
ANDY:
Which means?
NIGEL:
Catastrophe.
(whispers)
Just, uh-- Just go.
-I just don't understand.
I'm appalled.
-It's absurd. Appalled.
-You deal with it.
-I'll talk to him.
So because she pursed
her lips, he's gonna change
his entire collection?
You still don't get it,
do you?
Her opinion
is the only one
that matters.
-Call my husband
and confirm dinner.
-At Pastis? Done.
And I'll need
a change of clothes.
Well, I've already
messengered your outfit
over to the shoot.
Fine. And, Andrea,
I would like you
to deliver the Book
to my home tonight.
-Have Emily
give you the key.
-Mm-hmm.
-Guard this with your life.
-Of course.
You know, if I can
deliver the Book,
that means I must have
done something right.
I'm not a psycho.
Oh, and, you know,
she called me Andrea?
I mean, she didn't
call me Emily, which is--
Isn't that great?
Yeah, whoopee.
Right.
Now, it's very important
that you do exactly what
I'm about to tell you.
Oh. Okay.
EMILY: The Book is assembled
by 10:00, 10:30,
and you must
wait around for it
until then.
You will be delivering
Miranda's dry cleaning
with the Book.
Now, the car will
take you straight
to Miranda's townhouse.
You let yourself in.
Andrea. You do not
talk to anyone.
Do not look at anyone.
This is of
the utmost importance.
You must be invisible.
-Do you understand?
-Uh-huh.
You open the door
and you walk across the foyer.
You hang the dry cleaning
in the closet
across from the staircase.
-Uh--
-And you leave the Book
on the table with the flowers.
(panting)
-Shit!
-GIRL: It's that door
to the left.
Okay.
(whispers) Thank you.
-You can give
the Book to us.
-Shh. Which-- Which table?
-It's okay. Come on up.
-No, I can't. I can't.
-What? It's okay.
-Come on.
-Yeah, come on.
It's okay.
-Please stop talking.
Or you can bring
the Book upstairs.
Emily does it all the time.
She does? Right.
She does, all the time.
Yeah? Okay.
(giggling)
MIRANDA: What did you
expect me to do, walk out in
the middle of a cover shoot?
MAN: I rushed out of
an investment committee meeting,
and I sat there waiting
for you for almost an hour.
I told you the cell phones
didn't work.
Nobody could get
a signal out.
MAN: I knew what everyone in
that restaurant was thinking--
there he is,
waiting for her again.
-Okay, okay! Okay, okay.
-Oh, no. Shh!
It really wasn't
that big a deal.
I promise.
The twins said hello,
so I said hello back.
-Then I went up the stairs
to give her the Book and--
-You went upstairs?
Oh, my God. Why didn't you
just climb into bed with her
and ask for a bedtime story?
Okay, I made a mistake.
I know.
Andrea,
you don't understand.
If you get fired,
that might jeopardize
Paris for me.
If that happens, I will search
every Blimpie's in the tristate
area until I track you down.
She's gonna fire me?
I don't know.
She's not happy.
MIRANDA: Andrea?
(snaps fingers)
Miranda,
about last night, I--
I need the new
Harry Potter book
for the twins.
Okay. Okay. I'll go down
to Barnes & Noble right now.
Did you fall down and
smack your little head
on the pavement?
Not that I can recall.
We have all the published
Harry Potter books. The twins
want to know what happens next.
You want the unpublished
manuscript?
We know everyone in publishing.
It shouldn't be a problem,
should it?
And you can do anything, right?
(cell phone rings)
Yes, Bobbsey.
I know, baby.
Mommy's working very hard
to get it for you.
She doesn't get it.
I could call frickin'
J.K. Rowling herself.
I'm not gonna get a copy
of that book.
My girls are leaving
on the train for their
grandmother's at 4:00,
so the book better be here
no later than 3:00.
-Of course!
-And I would like my steak
here in 15 minutes.
No problem!
(panting)
Okay. I have four hours
to get the impossible
manuscript.
Smith & Wollensky's
doesn't open until 11:30.
How am I gonna get the steak?
Okay. I will be back
in 15 minutes.
-Wish me luck!
-No. Shan't.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
I've been on hold.
It's for Miranda Priestly.
It's very important.
Yes, I know
it's impossible to get,
but, well, I was wondering
if you could make
the impossible possible,
if that's
at all possible.
(laughing)
Yes, I'm calling about
the Harry Potter manuscript.
Uh, no. Unpublished.
Not a chance?
Tell her that it's
for Miranda Priestly.
'Cause I think
it makes a difference.
Let me call you back.
Hi, you probably don't
remember me. We met
at James Holt's party.
I'm Miranda Priestly's
assistant.
The Harry Potter manuscript?
Oh, you're kidding.
Uh, sorry to ask,
but I'm desperate.
Just tell her it can't be done.
You'll have to come up
with a Plan "B."
Well, this is Miranda Priestly
we're talking about.
There is no Plan "B."
There's only Plan "A."
Is she back?
Am I fired?
I rarely say this
to people who aren't me,
but you have got
to calm down.
Bloody hell!
Coat, bag.
What's that?
Oh, I don't want that.
I'm having lunch with Irv.
I'll be back at 3:00.
I'd like my Starbucks waiting.
Oh, and if you don't have
that Harry Potter book by then,
don't even bother
coming back.
(phone rings)
Hello.
Quit? Are you sure?
I failed.
She's gonna fire me anyway.
-I might as well
beat her to the punch.
-Wow.
Andy, good for you.
Congratulations.
You're free.
-Yeah. Well, listen,
I'll call you later.
-Okay.
-(line clicks, phone rings)
-Hello.
I'm brilliant.
No, really.
Monuments should be erected
in my honor.
-You didn't.
-Oh, yes.
A friend of a friend
does the cover art,
and she happens
to have the manuscript.
Oh, no, 'cause that would mean
that I actually
did something right.
(chuckles)
It's just-- Ugh!
The thing is, Christian,
I was just--
Look, you want this thing,
you better hurry.
I'll meet you at the St. Regis.
-Excuse me.
-(horn honks)
-Welcome to the St. Regis.
May I assist you with anything?
-Oh. Yes.
-Uh, I'm meeting someone
at the King Cole Bar.
-Right this way.
Hi.
-You have one hour.
-Thank you.
One copy.
What are my twins
gonna do with that? Share?
Oh, no, I made two copies...
and had them covered,
reset and bound so that they
wouldn't look like manuscripts.
This is an extra copy
to have on file.
You know, just in case.
Well, where are these
fabulous copies?
I don't see them anywhere.
(whistle blows)
ANDY: They're with
the twins, on the train
on the way to Grandma's.
Is there anything else
I can do for you?
Mm-mm.
That's all.
Okay.
(door opens)
-Hey.
-Hey. I went to Dean & Deluca.
Man, they charge,
like, five dollars
a strawberry there.
But I figure
since you quit your job,
we should celebrate.
-Listen, Nate.
-Wait a minute.
You quit your job,
but you're still working
on the twins' science project?
Well, that's big of you.
Okay, after we talked,
I realized
it doesn't make sense
throwing away all those
months of hard work.
I just had a moment
of weakness, that's all.
Yeah, well, either that,
or your job sucks
and your boss is a wacko.
All right. Whatever.
It's your job.
Nate.
Come on.
I'm still
the same person I was.
I still want
the same things.
Okay?
-Mm-hmm.
-I promise. Same Andy,
better clothes.
-(giggles)
-I like the old clothes.
Really?
Well, what about
these necklaces?
Do you like them?
No? And this dress,
it's new.
Eh.
Well, there is one
other thing that's new
that I thought you might like.
But, uh--
What about this?
(up-tempo music playing)
You don't like it.
I should better do--
No, no, no, no.
♪ But we're
never gonna survive ♪
♪ Unless we get
a little crazy ♪
♪ No, we're never
gonna survive ♪
♪ Unless we are
a little crazy ♪
Is this number two look?
This is number two?
-Hi.
-Hi. All right.
Turn around for me, darling.
Oh, I get it.
I get it. I get it.
The piece is called
"Urban Jungle," right?
Yes, the modern woman
unleashes the animal within
to take on the big city.
(growls)
Good. Go.
(sighs) Sometimes
I can't believe I talk
about this crap all day.
-Bobby, come here.
Let me see.
-Oh, thank you.
-Make sure Miranda gets these
as soon as possible.
-Mm-hmm.
And tell her I switched
in the Dior for the Rocha.
-Oh, great. Can't wait.
-Excuse me.
-Can we adjust the attitude?
-I'm sorry.
-Don't make me feed you
to one of the models.
-I'm sorry.
It's a busy day.
My personal life
is hanging by a thread,
that's all.
Join the club. That's
what happens when you start
doing well at work, darling.
Let me know
when your whole life
goes up in smoke.
That means it's time
for a promotion.
No. All right, February,
back of the issue.
Did anybody speak
with Salma's people yet?
Yes, but she'd rather
do a summer cover because
she has a movie coming out.
No. Also, I'm pulling
the Toobin piece
on the Supreme Court women--
(inhales) woman.
And I need to see a new
draft on that piece
about shopping
for a plastic surgeon--
It's dull.
And this layout for
the Winter Wonderland spread.
Not wonderful yet.
Oh, okay.
I-I'll look at it.
What about Testino?
Where are we on that?
Zac Posen's doing
some very sculptural suits.
So I suggested
that, uh, Testino shoot them
at the Noguchi Garden.
Perfect.
Thank God somebody
came to work today.
What about accessories
for April?
One thought I had
was enamel. Um, bangles,
pendants, earrings.
No. We did that two years ago.
What else?
Um, well, they're showing
a lot of florals right now,
so I was thinking--
Florals? For spring?
Groundbreaking.
But we thought
about shooting them
in an industrial space.
We thought the contrast
between the femininity
of the florals
and the more raw, rough-hewn
background would create this
wonderful tension between--
-No.
-Which?
-(Emily coughing)
-No.
(coughing continues)
Does anybody else
have anything
I can possibly use?
Antibacterial wipes perhaps?
(groans)
-How's the cold doing?
-Like death warmed up, actually.
(sniffles)
Oh, God.
It's the benefit tonight.
I've been looking forward
to it for months.
I refuse to be sick.
I'm wearing Valentino,
for crying out loud.
Right. Well, everybody
will be leaving soon
to get ready,
so I suggest you go
and drop Miranda's Fendi bag
off at the showroom,
and then I suppose
you can just go home.
Yeah? Oh, well,
that is great.
Perfect actually.
I need to get to Magnolia Bakery
before it closes.
It's Nate's birthday tonight.
So we're, uh,
having a little party
for him.
Yeah, I'm hearing this,
and I wanna hear this.
Bye.
I love my job.
(chattering)
(cell phone rings)
Hello?
Before the benefit tonight,
I need to make sure
that you're both fully prepped
on the guest list.
But I thought that
only the first assistant
went to the benefit.
Only when the first assistant
hasn't decided to become
an incubus of viral plague.
You'll come
and help Emily.
-That's all.
-Right.
These are all of the guests.
Miranda invites everyone.
We have to make sure
that they all think she knows
exactly who they are.
And I've been studying
for weeks.
I have to learn
all these by tonight?
No, don't be silly, Andrea.
These too.
Look, you better
just start without me, okay?
I'll get there as soon as I can.
Andy, come on,
it's his birth--
Okay, but hurry.
Oh, please, believe me, I will.
This is the last thing
that I wanna--
Ooh, I love that.
Uh, I'll call you the second
I'm leaving, okay?
-Will that fit me?
-Oh, yeah.
A little Crisco
and some fishing line,
and we're in business.
(sarcastic chuckle)
(electronic dance music playing)
Well, nothing really.
I mean, this is--
I mean, really,
this is the social event
of the season.
♪ I'm too near
to make it clear ♪
♪ Emotional suicide ♪
♪ Is this love
I'm thinking of ♪
-Oh, oh, my God.
Andy, you look so chic.
-♪ I know that ♪
-Oh, thanks, Em.
-You look so thin.
-Do I?
-Yeah.
Oh, it's for Paris.
I'm on this new diet.
It's very effective.
Well, I don't eat anything.
And then when I feel like
I'm about to faint,
I eat a cube of cheese.
-Well, it's definitely working.
-I know.
I'm just one stomach flu
away from my goal weight.
(electronic dance music playing)
♪ Look at us, we're beautiful ♪
♪ All the people
push and pull but ♪
♪ Let's just go out and ride ♪
♪ Talk about the things
we try ♪
That's John Folger,
the new artistic director
of the Chelsea Rep.
-John, thanks for coming.
-Hey, there.
JOHN: Oh, thank you.
It's always nice seeing you.
-Stop fidgeting.
-I'm sorry. I'm so late.
Just deal with it.
You have to be here.
Emily, come here.
Isn't that Jacqueline Follet
from French Runway?
Oh, my God,
and Miranda hates her.
She was supposed to arrive
after Miranda left.
-I didn't-- Oh.
-Yeah.
-Miranda, fabulous event
as always.
-You brought Jacqueline.
-Surprise.
-Quelle surprise.
Oh, wonderful.
We're so happy you were able
to come to our little gathering.
Of course.
I plan my whole year
around this.
Well, we're so grateful
that you do.
-Ciao.
-Have you gotten my note?
Yes, I did.
We'll discuss it on Wednesday.
-Yes, I agree.
No business tonight.
-Not tonight.
-Enjoy.
-(sniffles)
Em.
Oh, thanks.
Thanks.
Oh, um-- Oh, my God.
I just can't remember
what his name is.
I just saw his name
this morning on the list.
It's-- Oh, I know this.
It's something to do with--
Wait, he was--
he was part of the--
Oh, God, I know this. Um--
It's Ambassador Franklin,
and that's the woman that
he left his wife for, Rebecca.
-Rebecca. Ambassador.
-Miranda.
-You look fabulous.
-Oh, very kind.
-Thank you.
-(chattering continues)
-Look at you.
-Hello.
You're--
You're a vision.
-Oh. (scoffs)
-Thank God I saved your job.
(stammers, chuckles)
You know, I figured out
a few things on my own too.
Turns out, I'm not as nice
as you thought.
I hope not.
Well, if it weren't
for the stupid boyfriend,
I'd have to whisk you away
right here and now.
-Do you actually say things
like that to people?
-Evidently.
(giggles)
Well, I gotta go.
Are you sure? 'Cause my editor
for New York Magazine is inside,
and, you know,
I could introduce you two.
-You sent over your stuff
for me to look at? Remember?
-Yeah.
All right, I gotta admit,
I only read a couple. It was
a very large packet you sent.
-Yeah.
-But what I did read
wasn't half bad.
And, you know, I think--
I think you have a talent, Andy.
He should meet you.
Why don't you come in?
Just for one drink.
Um, okay, yeah.
I guess I could for one--
No, I can't.
I'm sorry,
but I have to go.
All right. Give my best
to the boyfriend.
Roy, I'm sorry.
Can you go any faster?
I'm sure Nate will understand.
Yeah.
(TV, indistinct)
Hey.
Happy birthday.
Nate, I'm so sorry.
I kept trying to leave,
but there was a lot going on.
And, you know,
I didn't have a choice.
Don't worry about it.
(grunts)
I'm gonna go to bed.
Can we at least
talk about this?
You look really pretty.
MIRANDA:
Andrea?
-Do you have the Book?
-Oh. Uh--
Mm.
Paris is
the most important week
of my entire year.
I need the best
possible team with me.
That no longer
includes Emily.
Wait.
You want me to--
(stammering) No, Miranda.
(exhales)
Emily would die.
Her whole life
is about Paris.
She hasn't eaten in weeks.
I-I can't... do that.
Miranda, I can't.
If you don't go,
I'll assume you're not serious
about your future
at Runway or...
any other publication.
The decision's yours.
That's all.
(down-tempo music playing)
♪ Fill these spaces
up with days ♪
♪ In my room ♪
♪ You can go
you can stay ♪
(laughing)
♪ I can't sleep ♪
♪ I can't speak to you ♪
♪ Now these years
locked in my drawer ♪
♪ I'll open to see ♪
-♪ Just to be sure ♪
-Hey, Andy.
-Hey.
-You coming to bed
anytime soon?
Uh, yeah.
Five minutes, okay?
♪ I can't speak to you ♪
♪ I can't sleep ♪
(sighs)
(fax printing)
(clears throat)
Andrea, don't forget
to tell Emily.
Do it now.
-(line ringing)
-Don't pick up.
Don't pick up. Don't pick--
-Hi.
-Emily.
-Hi, hi. Sorry I'm late.
It's just Miranda wanted
some scarves from Hermès.
And she did tell me yesterday,
but I forgot like an idiot.
And so I freaked out,
of course.
Emily, Emily,
I-I need to talk to you.
I called Martine at home,
and she opened the shop early.
Whoa! I'm sorry.
She opened the shop early
for me, so I got them,
which is great.
Okay. Um, Emily,
wh-when you come in,
there's something
I have to talk to you about.
-Well, I hope it's not
another Miranda problem.
-Not exactly.
Well, good, because
I've got so much to deal with
before I go. I swear to God--
-(gasps)
-(horn honks)
-(people exclaiming)
-WOMAN: Oh, my God!
Emily?
(woman on P.A., indistinct)
(elevator bell dings)
I don't care if she was
gonna fire you or beat you
with a red-hot poker!
You should have said no.
Emily, I didn't have a choice.
-Oh. Please.
-You know how she is.
-That is a pathetic excuse.
-(door opens)
Thanks.
Do you know
what really just...
gets me about
this whole thing,
is that, you know, you're
the one who said you don't
really care about this stuff.
And you don't really care
about fashion. You just
wanna be a journalist.
What a pile of bollocks!
Emily, I know you're mad.
I don't blame you.
Face it, you sold your soul
the day you put on that first
pair of Jimmy Choo's.
I saw it. And you know
what really just kills me
about this whole thing,
is the clothes
that you're gonna get.
I mean,
you don't deserve them.
You eat carbs,
for Christ's sake.
God, it's so unfair!
-Emily.
-Just go.
-Emily, I--
-I said go!
(sighs)
-DOUG: You are going to Paris
for the couture shows?
-ANDY: Mm-hmm.
-That's the coolest
fashion event of the year.
-Mm-hmm.
-I mean, who are you
going to see, Galliano?
-Yeah.
-And Lagerfeld
and Nicholas Ghesquiere.
-Yep.
-Yes. Okay,
now you're scaring me.
-(chuckles)
-Hey.
-This show is amazing.
I am so proud of you.
-LILY: Thank you.
Okay, start with
the photos in the back
and work your way forward.
That is the way
I designed it.
It is brilliant.
You will love it.
-Of course.
-And you,
I have somebody
I want you to meet, okay?
-Ooh, art and sex.
-Lead the way.
-See you later.
-Okay.
(down-tempo music playing)
♪ I've no regrets ♪
♪ Every single work I find ♪
♪ Don't hold our breath ♪
-♪ Wait for another sign ♪
-Hey. Hey, Miranda girl.
-Hi.
-I was just thinking
about you.
Oh, come on.
-It's true.
-No.
I'm profiling Gaultier
for Interview
and, uh, making
my Paris plans.
I found myself wondering
if, uh, you were gonna be there.
Well, actually,
um, I am going.
Great. I'm staying
in a fantastic little hotel
in the Seventh,
right across the street
from the falafel restaurant
that will change your life.
(chuckles) I'm sorry.
I'll be too busy working.
You'll have to find
someone else's life
to change.
Well, that's just it.
I'm beginning to wonder
if I can.
Lily.
Lily, he's just a guy
I know from work.
-Yeah, that looked like work.
-Look, you're making
a big deal out of--
You know, the Andy I know
is madly in love with Nate,
is always
five minutes early...
and thinks, I don't know,
Club Monaco is couture.
For the last 16 years,
I've known everything
about that Andy.
But this person?
This "glamazon" who skulks
around in corners...
with some random
hot fashion guy?
I don't get her.
-Lily.
-Have fun in Paris.
You going to Paris?
Uh, yeah.
It just happened.
I thought Paris
was a big deal
for Emily or--
Great. Now you're gonna
give me a hard time too?
Hey, Andy. Andy!
-Andy, what the hell
is wrong with you?
-I-I didn't have a choice, okay?
-Miranda asked me,
and I couldn't say no.
-I know.
That's your answer
for everything lately,
"I didn't have a choice."
-Like this job
was forced on you.
-Nate, I get it, okay?
Like you don't make
these decisions yourself.
You're mad because
I work late all the time and
I missed your birthday party.
-And I'm sorry.
-Oh, come on.
What am I, four?
You-- You hate Runway
and Miranda.
And you think
fashion is stupid.
You've made that clear.
Andy, I make port wine
reductions all day.
I'm not exactly
in the Peace Corps.
You know, I wouldn't care
if you were out there
pole dancing all night,
as long as you did it
with a little integrity.
You used to say
this was just a job.
You used to make fun
of the Runway girls.
What happened?
Now you've become
one of them.
-That's absurd.
-That's okay.
That's fine.
Just own up to it.
And then we can stop
pretending like we have
anything in common anymore.
-You don't mean that,
do you?
-No, I do.
Well, maybe this trip
is coming at a good time.
Maybe we should
take a break.
Nate?
(cell phone ringing)
I'm sorry.
Just... one second?
You know, in case
you were wondering,
the person whose calls
you always take, that's
the relationship you're in.
I hope you two
are very happy together.
(cell phone continues ringing)
Hello, Miranda.
(up-tempo music playing)
♪ In the city ♪
♪ Of blinding lights ♪
♪ I'm getting ready ♪
♪ To leave the ground ♪
♪ Oh, you look so beautiful ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ In the city ♪
♪ Of blinding lights ♪
♪ The more you know
the less you feel ♪
♪ Some pray for, others steal ♪
♪ Blessings not just
for the ones who kneel ♪
♪ Luckily ♪
(chattering)
Pardon. Miranda.
-(speaking Italian)
-Maestro. Mmm.
How are you?
So glad to see you.
Thank you for coming.
-You like the collection?
-Absolutely. I think
it's the best in years.
-This is very important for me.
Very, very important.
-I'm very happy for you.
-This is my new Emily.
-Hello. How do you do?
-I'm good. Pleasure.
-Nice to meet you.
You love the show?
-Miranda. This way!
-(clamoring)
Miranda. Nigel.
Fashion's great gatekeepers.
Miranda, what is Runway's
position on French fashion
versus American fashion?
-I've been thinking--
-Oh.
-You still owe me
for Harry Potter.
-Oh, do I?
Of course you do.
Are you working tonight?
Oh! No, actually Miranda
has a dinner.
Great, you're free.
Oh, but there is the problem
of le boyfriend.
Wait, don't tell me.
The boyfriend non plus?
Je suis tres, très désolé.
Oh, you're so full of it.
You're not désolé at all.
No, not even a little.
What time should I pick you up?
-Uh-- Yeah.
-I'll call you.
Oh.
Oh, there you are.
(clears throat)
We need to go over
the seating, uh, chart
for the luncheon.
Okay.
Um, yeah, sure.
I have it right here.
By all means,
move at a glacial pace.
You know how that thrills me.
Okay.
So...
first of all, we need to
move Snoop Dogg to my table.
But your table's full.
Stephen isn't coming.
Oh, Stephen is--
So I don't need to fetch
Stephen from the airport
tomorrow?
Well, if you speak to him
and he decides to rethink
the divorce,
then, yes, fetch away.
You're very fetching,
so go fetch.
And then when
we get back to New York,
we need to contact, um...
...Leslie to see what she can do
to minimize the press...
...on all this.
Another divorce...
...splashed across Page Six.
I can just imagine what
they're gonna write about me.
"The Dragon Lady,"
"career-obsessed."
"Snow Queen drives away
another Mr. Priestly."
Rupert Murdoch
should cut me a check
for all the papers
I sell for him.
Anyway, I don't--
I don't really care
what anybody writes about me.
But my-- my girls, I just--
It's just so unfair
to the girls.
It's just...
another disappointment,
another letdown,
another father... figure...
(chuckles) ...gone.
Anyway, the point is--
(clears throat)
The point is--
(sighs)
The point is
we really need to figure out
where to place Donatella,
because she's barely
speaking to anyone.
I'm so sorry, Miranda.
If you want me to cancel
your evening, I can.
Don't be ridiculous.
Why would we do that?
Um, is--
Is there anything else
I can do?
Your job.
That's all.
(knocking)
Hi. I need Miranda's itinerary
for tomorrow.
-Okay. Come on in.
-All right? Thanks.
-Who put that
together for you?
-This?
Oh, it's just--
it's just something
I threw on.
Turn around.
Let me see. Turn.
-Mm. Incroyable.
-Yeah?
-It's really just--
No, it's-- No, gorgeous.
-Yeah? Okay, good.
Really. I think that
my work here is done.
Oh.
We're going to celebrate.
I'm going to get
some champagne.
Okay.
What are we toasting?
We are toasting, my dear,
to the dream job.
The one that
a million girls wanted.
Which I got months ago.
I'm not talking
about you.
Mm-hmm.
-James Holt--
-Yeah.
Massimo Corteleoni...
...is investing
in James's company
and taking it global.
-Mm-hmm.
-Bags, shoes, fragrances--
the works.
And James
needs a partner.
And that partner
would be me.
-Does Miranda--
-No, no, Miranda knows,
because--
-Oh.
-Oh, she put me up for it!
God, no. Can you imagine?
But-- But--
But you're leaving.
-Mm-hmm.
-I can't imagine Runway
without you.
I know, I know,
but I'm so excited though.
This is the first time in
18 years I'm going to be able to
call the shots in my own life.
Oh, my God!
I'm going to be able
to come to Paris
and actually see Paris.
Well, congratulations.
-Huh? Oh.
-Nigel, you deserve it.
You bet your size-six ass.
(guffaws)
-Four.
-Really?
-(glasses clink)
-Cheers.
-Cheers to you.
-To us.
-Let me see that.
-(giggles)
(woman singing in French)
Okay, I just wanna say that yes,
there are things Miranda does
that I don't agree with, but--
-Come on. You hate her.
Just admit it to me.
-No.
She's a--
She's a notorious sadist,
and not--
not in a good way.
Okay, she's tough,
but if Miranda were a man,
no one would notice
anything about her, except
how great she is at her job.
(chuckles)
I'm sorry. I can't--
-I can't believe this.
You're defending her?
-Yeah.
The wide-eyed girl
peddling her earnest
newspaper stories?
You, my friend,
are crossing over
to the dark side.
I resent that.
-You shouldn't. It's sexy.
-Sexy?
-Really?
-Really.
So do you-- do you know
where we're going?
-'Cause I'm lost.
-Yeah.
Yeah, don't worry.
I know this city
like the back of my hand.
It's my favorite place
in the whole world.
You know, Gertrude Stein
once said,
"America is my country,
and Paris is my hometown."
-(laughs)
-It's true.
What do you do?
Do you just write stuff
like that down
and then file it away
to use on us girls?
-I'm Christian Thompson.
That's my way.
-That's your way. Right.
I work freelance.
I have a lot of free time
on my hands.
You know,
I never understood
why everyone
was so crazy about Paris,
but... it is so beautiful.
(giggles)
Mm. I-I can't.
I'm sorry.
I can't. You know,
Nate and I just split up
a couple days ago, and I can't.
Ooh.
I've had too much wine.
And my hearing-- vision--
judgment's impaired.
No, I barely know you.
I'm in a strange city.
I... am out of excuses.
Thank God.
(groans)
(gasps)
Yes.
Oh, shoot.
(door opens)
Bonjour, madame.
Uh, what the hell is this?
What does it look like?
It's a mock-up.
Yeah. Of?
Of what American Runway
will look like
when Jacqueline Follet
is the new editor in chief.
Wh-- They're replacing Miranda?
Yeah. And she's
bringing me in to run
all the editorial content.
You're really surprised?
Jacqueline's a lot younger
than Miranda. She has
a fresher take on things.
Not to mention American Runway's
one of the most expensive books
in the business.
Jacqueline does the same thing
for a lot less money.
And Irv--
Irv's a businessman, you know.
Miranda will be devastated.
Her whole life is about Runway.
He can't do that to her.
It's done.
Irv's gonna tell Miranda
after the party for James.
And she has no idea?
She's a big girl.
She'll be fine.
Shi--
I have to go.
Andy.
Andy, it's done.
Baby, it's done.
I'm not your baby.
-(phone ringing)
-Allo.
Oh! Oh!
Thank God you're there.
-(sighs) Excuse me?
-I need to talk to you
right away.
It's about
Jacqueline Follet.
Shit! Oh, shit!
Shit, shit, shit!
-Yes.
-Mr. Ravitz, I'm so sorry
to bother you. I was wondering--
Have you completely
lost your mind?
-I need to talk to you.
-Do not disturb me again.
But, um,
it's just for one--
Miranda!
(horn honks)
Miranda. Miranda.
Wait, I need to talk to you.
Irv is making Jacqueline Follet
the editor in chief of Runway.
Christian Thompson told me
he's gonna work for her.
Irv is going to tell you today.
I thought maybe if I told you,
that you could fix it.
Do I smell freesias?
What? No.
I-I specifically told them--
If I see freesias anywhere,
I will be very disappointed.
For 72 years, Runway
has been more than a magazine.
It has been a beacon
of elegance and grace.
Miranda Priestly is
the finest possible guardian
of that beacon,
setting a standard
that inspires people
across the globe.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you Miranda Priestly.
Thank you,
my dear friend.
Bonjour.
(chuckles)
Thank you very much
for coming today
to help celebrate
our dear friend, James Holt.
But before I talk
to you about James
and his many
accomplishments,
I would like first
to share some news with you.
Um, as many of you know,
uh, recently
Massimo Corteleoni
has agreed
to finance the expansion
of the James Holt label,
transforming the work
of this visionary artist
into a global brand,
which is really
an exciting enterprise.
Runway and James Holt
share many things in common,
chief among them,
a commitment to excellence.
And so, it should come
as no surprise
that when the time came
for James to choose
the new president
of James Holt International,
he chose from within
the Runway family.
And it's
my great happiness today
to announce to you all
that that person
is my friend and
longtime esteemed colleague,
Jacqueline Follet.
Thank you. Merci.
And now to the main event,
our celebration of James Holt.
We at Runway are very proud
to have been--
When the time is right,
she'll pay me back.
You sure about that?
No.
But I hope
for the best.
I have to.
(people clamoring)
You thought I didn't know.
I've known what was happening
for quite some time.
It just took me a little while
to find a suitable alternative
for Jacqueline.
And that James Holt job
was so absurdly overpaid
that, of course, she
jumped at it. (chuckles)
So I just had to tell
Irv that Jacqueline
was unavailable.
The truth is, there is no one
that can do what I do,
including her.
Any of the other choices
would have found
that job impossible,
and the magazine
would have suffered.
(sighs)
Especially because of the list.
The list of designers,
photographers,
editors, writers, models,
all of whom were found by me,
nurtured by me
and have promised me
they will follow me
whenever and if ever
I choose to leave Runway.
(chuckles)
So he reconsidered.
But I was very,
very impressed
by how intently
you tried to warn me.
I never thought
I would say this, Andrea,
but I really--
I see a great deal
of myself in you.
You can see beyond
what people want
and what they need,
and you can choose
for yourself.
I don't think
I'm like that.
I--
I couldn't do
what you did to Nigel,
Miranda.
I couldn't do
something like that.
Mm. You already did.
To Emily.
That's not what I--
No, that was--
that was different.
I didn't have a choice.
Oh, no, you chose.
You chose to get ahead.
You want this life,
those choices are necessary.
But what if...
this isn't what I want?
I mean, what if I don't
want to live the way you live?
Don't be ridiculous, Andrea.
Everybody wants this.
Everybody wants to be us.
(reporters clamoring)
(mid-tempo music playing)
(cell phone ringing)
I have to be
at work in 20 minutes.
What's up?
Well, I just--
I wanted to say
that you were right
about everything.
That...
I turned my back on my friends
and my family
and everything
I believed in,
and-- and for what?
For shoes and shirts
and jackets and belts.
Nate.
I'm sorry.
I--
(clears throat)
I flew up to Boston
while you were gone.
I interviewed
at the Oak Room.
And?
And you're looking
at their new sous-chef.
-I'm moving up there
in a couple weeks.
-That's great. Congratulations.
I don't know what I'm gonna
do without those late-night
grilled cheeses, but--
I'm pretty sure
they have bread in Boston.
May even have Jarlsberg.
We might be able
to figure something out.
You think?
Yeah.
So, what about you?
I mean, what are you
gonna do now?
Actually, I, uh-- I have
a job interview today.
-Oh, yeah?
-Mm-hm.
That's what
you're wearing?
Shut up.
I like this.
-Andy, Greg Hill.
-Hello.
Come on.
These clips are excellent.
This thing
on the Janitors' Union,
that's exactly what we do here.
My only question is, Runway?
You were there
for less than a year.
What the hell
kind of a blip is that?
Learned a lot.
In the end, though,
I kind of screwed it up.
I called over there
for a reference, left word
with some snooty girl.
Next thing you know,
I got a fax from
Miranda Priestly herself,
saying that
of all the assistants
she's ever had,
you were, by far,
her biggest disappointment.
And, if I don't hire you,
I am an idiot.
You must have done
something right.
-(beeping)
-(phone ringing)
Miranda Priestly's office.
Hey, Emily, it's Andy.
Don't hang up.
I have a favor to ask you.
You have a favor
to ask of me?
Yeah. The thing is, I have
all these clothes from Paris,
and I don't have anyplace
to wear them,
so I was wondering
if you could take them
off my hands.
Well, I don't know.
It's a huge imposition.
And I'll have to
get them taken in.
I mean, they'll drown me.
But I suppose I could
help you out. I will have Roy
pick them up this afternoon.
Thanks, Em.
I appreciate it.
Good luck.
You have some very
large shoes to fill.
I hope you know that.
I don't understand
why it is so challenging...
to get my car
when I ask for it.
(chuckles)
Go.
Captioned by:
Axium Digital, Inc.